yanmar.com 2019-02-05

# Privacy Statement | Yanmar USA

This Privacy Statement (the “Statement”) sets out how Yanmar America Corporation, headquartered at 101 International Parkway and our group companies, subsidiaries and associated offices worldwide (“Yanmar”, “we”, “us”, “our”, etc.), collect and use the personally identifiable information of users of our websites and services (each a “User”, “you”, “your”, etc.). By using our services and, where applicable, by providing consents for specific purposes, you consent to the use of your data as described in this Statement.  
Please do not supply any private information if you do not agree with this policy.

### Collection of your Personal Information

Yanmar may sometimes request Private Information of our customers through this site for the purpose of registering Yanmar users, receiving customer orders for various services, responding to customer inquiries, providing special offers to its customers, disseminating promotional campaigns, and similar purposes directly related to Yanmar products and services.

In order to respond to an individual’s inquiry or request, the individual user agrees and understands that it may be necessary for Yanmar to share their Private Information with other Yanmar group companies. In addition, Private Information may be disclosed to relevant distribution companies to facilitate sending products or reference materials. In such cases, the individual consents to such sharing of Private Information and Yanmar shall impose on such companies the obligation not to use the Private Information of our customers for any other purpose.

We accept inquiries from customers on this site. Reference materials will only be sent to those customers who request them.

Whether a customer supplies Private Information to Yanmar is completely voluntary. By providing their Private Information, the customer agrees that Yanmar may use such information within the bounds of this privacy policy. However, Yanmar agrees that no Private Information will be disclosed in any form or sold to third parties without that person’s prior consent.

We collect personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, first and last name, position, employer details, home or work address or telephone number and other information. We also collect anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by us. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by us for the operation of our services, to maintain quality of the services, and to provide general statistics regarding use of our websites.

If you use our services, such as interactive services, we may collect information about you or other individuals included in your posts, materials, messages or other contributions (as defined in our **Terms of Use** ) which you may share with other Users or the public. We ask that you respect the data privacy rights of any individuals who are referred to, or whose personally identifiable information is included in, your contributions.

Most of the above mentioned information will constitute  **“Personally Identifiable Information’  **or  **“Personal Data”** , depending on the extent to which such information is protected by privacy or data protection laws in the relevant country.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose Personally Identifiable Information through our public discussion or message boards, this information may be collected and used by others.

### Use of your Personally Identifiable Information

We will only process your Personally Identifiable Information, in accordance with applicable law, for the following purposes:

  * to operate our websites and deliver the services you have requested, including, without limitation, our interactive services which you use;
  * sending you personalized marketing communications to inform you of other products or services available from us and our affiliates, exhibitors and partners;
  * to contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered;
  * responding to your queries;
  * confirmation of registration or purchase;
  * to include your name, phone number and mailing address in our directory;
  * to create marketing materials including images or video footage of you as an attendee of our functions;
  * handling any job application that you may make to us;
  * enabling our suppliers and service providers to carry out certain functions on our behalf, including statistical analysis, verification, technical, logistical or other functions;
  * ensuring the security of our business, preventing or detecting fraud or abuses of our website;
  * developing and improving our products and services, for example, by reviewing visits to our website and its various subpages to ascertain demand for specific content; and
  * to comply with applicable law, for example, in response to a request from a court or regulatory body, where such request is made in accordance with the law.

The legal basis for us processing your Personally Identifiable Information for the purposes described above will typically be because you have provided us with your consent. However, we may also rely on other legal grounds, for example, where the processing is necessary:

  * to fulfill a request that we have received from you;
  * for the legitimate business interests of us and our affiliates or partners; or
  * for compliance with our legal obligations.

### Opt-out

You may opt-out of our email marketing lists by following the directions at the bottom of our emails. Yanmar has a number of products in which we allow you to opt-out selectively. To remove a specific postal or email address from all of Yanmar’s marketing communications, you may send a request to  **marketing@yanmar.com**. If you are contacted by our exhibitors or our partners please opt out with them directly and where such request is received by us, we will endeavor to pass on to such partners.

Opting-out of promotional mailings will not affect delivery of your requested products or services.

### Use of Cookies

Our website uses “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your computer’s hard disk, mobile phone or other device by a web page server. Cookies do not damage your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. However, we also use cookies to send you advertisements that may be of interest to you.

We use several types of cookies on our website:

_Strictly necessary cookies_

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around our website and use its features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for cannot be provided. They are deleted when you close the browser.

_Performance cookies_

These cookies collect information in an anonymous form about how visitors use our website. They allow us to recognize and count the number of visitors and help us understand which pages are the most popular and where visitors spend most of their time.

_Functionality cookies_

These cookies allow our website to remember choices you make, such as your name, the region you are in or the pages you have viewed. They are used to provide enhanced and more personal features.

If you personalize our pages, or register with our website or services, a persistent cookie helps us to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to our website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the features that you customized. Persistent cookies will be kept on your device until their expiry or manual deletion.

_Targeting or advertising cookies_

These cookies allow us and our advertisers to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. They remember that you have visited our website and may help us in compiling your profile.

_Social Media cookies_

These cookies allow you to connect with social media networks such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Pinterest and Google+.

We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our website and to improve the service we offer to you. An IP address is a numeric code that identifies your computer on a network, or in this case, the internet. Your IP address might also be used to gather broad demographic information. We may perform IP lookups to determine which domain you are coming from to more accurately gauge our Users’ demographics.

Information from these types of cookies and technologies or about website usage may be combined with information about you from any other source.

_Your consent to place cookies_

We assume that you are happy for us to place cookies on your device. However, if you, or another User of your device, wish to withdraw your consent at any time, you have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of our services or the websites you visit.

When you arrive on our website a pop-up message will appear asking for your consent to place advertising cookies on your device. In order to provide your consent, please click on the button in the pop-up message. Once your consent has been provided, this message will not appear again when you revisit. If you, or another User of your computer, wish to withdraw your consent at any time, you can do so by altering your browser settings.

### Disclosure of your Personal Data

There are circumstances where we wish to disclose or are compelled to disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to third parties. This will only take place in accordance with the applicable law and for the purposes listed above. These scenarios include disclosure:

  * to our parent company or subsidiaries
  * to our partners who request a list on a one-time basis for marketing purposes. All such third parties are prohibited from using your Personally Identifiable Information, except for specific and limited marketing purposes and to provide services to us, and they are required to maintain the security and confidentiality of your information. Please opt-out if you no longer consent to your information being shared in this way; if applicable
  * to other Users or the public as you may request using our interactive services, or as is necessary in order to resolve any disputes in relation to your contributions to our websites and services;
  * to our outsourced service providers or suppliers to facilitate the provision of our services, for example, the disclosure to our database hosting provider for the safe keeping of your Personally Identifiable Information, webhosting provider through which your Personally Identifiable Information may be collected;
  * to third party service providers and consultants in order to protect the security or integrity of our business, including our databases and systems and for business continuity reasons;
  * to another legal entity, on a temporary or permanent basis, for the purposes of a joint venture, collaboration, financing, sale, merger, reorganization, change of legal form, dissolution or similar event. In the case of a merger or sale, your Personally Identifiable Information will be permanently transferred to a successor company;
  * to public authorities where we are required by law to do so; and
  * to any other third party where you have provided your consent.

### International transfer of Personal Data

We may transfer your Personally Identifiable Information to a third party in countries outside the country in which it was originally collected for further processing in accordance with the purposes set out above. In particular, your Personally Identifiable Information may be transferred throughout our group and to our outsourced service providers located abroad.

In these circumstances we will, as may be required by applicable law, ensure that your privacy rights are adequately protected by appropriate technical, organization, contractual or other lawful means. If you are located in the European Economic Area, you may contact us for a copy of the safeguards which we have put in place to protect your Personally Identifiable Information and privacy rights in these circumstances.

### Retention of Personal Data

Your Personally Identifiable Information will be retained for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes listed above or as required by applicable local law. Please contact us for further details of applicable retention periods.

We may keep an anonymized form of your Personally Identifiable Information, which will no longer refer to you, for statistical purposes without time limits, to the extent that we have a legitimate and lawful interest in doing so.

### Security of your Personally Identifiable Information

We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational measures in accordance with industry standards to safeguard your Personally Identifiable Information. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the _______________________ protocol. However, no security measure is completely secure (e.g. from malicious intrusion) and we are unable to guarantee complete security of your Personally Identifiable Information.

In order to improve the security of your Personally Identifiable Information and your User account, we would advise that you must choose a strong password to protect your account information and to change it regularly at reasonable intervals. Furthermore, you must exit from your User account at the end of each session, not allow your browser to save your login details and secure and limit access to your personal devices.

### Monitoring

We may monitor your use of our websites and services, including our interactive and communications services by intercepting, blocking, recording or otherwise accessing systems whether on a continuous or occasional basis, as permitted by applicable law. For example, where allowed by applicable law we may monitor the content of any messages sent to your User account by another User or external party and how your devices access our websites and services.

We monitor in order to ensure compliance with our legal obligations and good practice, your compliance with our Terms and policies, to gather information as part of investigations by regulatory bodies or in connection with legal proceedings or requests, to ensure confidentiality of commercially sensitive information, to operate firewalls, prevent viruses, malicious code and the downloading or use of executable software code, to prevent the downloading, copying, distribution or other use of obscene, offensive or illegal material (such as pornographic, racist or other discriminatory content), to restrict access to third-party websites, blogs and bulletin boards in accordance with applicable systems use policies, and to prevent unauthorized access and modifications to our systems.

You should have no expectation of privacy when using our services, including our interactive and communications services, because it will be subject to monitoring as set out above. However, we will comply with local laws in relation to your privacy. For example, if you are based in Europe, as far as is reasonably practical, we will not monitor or access the content of private messages or correspondence. Where we believe that such monitoring is justified and lawful, we will limit the number of people who have access to the information concerned.

### Interactive Services Complaints Procedure

If you believe that a User contribution posted on any of our interactive services is inaccurate or otherwise infringes upon your data privacy rights, please notify us by email to  **marketing@yanmar.com.** A notice will be valid if it includes:

  * documentation sufficiently confirming your identity;
  * your contact details;
  * a screenshot of the infringing material with a time and date stamp;
  * a signed statement explaining how the material infringes upon your data privacy rights; and
  * your suggestions as to how the infringing User should remedy his/her infringement.

Upon receipt of a valid notice, we will review your complaint and reply within 21 days. In our reply we may ask you for further information or inform you of what steps we have taken to resolve the matter.

### Links to other websites

You should be aware that when you are on our website, you could be directed to other websites that are beyond our control. There are links to other sites from our website that may take you outside our service. We cannot guarantee that the privacy statements of these websites meet our standards. As always, we recommend reading the privacy statements of any new website you go to online.

### Your rights and updating your Personally Identifiable Information

In certain countries, data protection law provides individuals with numerous rights, including the right to access, rectify, erase, restrict or object to the processing of, their Personally Identifiable Information. For more information about your rights, including your right to lodge a complaint, please visit the website of your local data protection authority.

If for any reason you wish to access, review, correct or delete the Personally Identifiable Information collected about you, you may do so by emailing:  **marketing@yanmar.com** You must be able to provide sufficient proof of your identity. Once identified, we will be happy to review, update or remove your information, as appropriate.

### Children

Please note that this website is not intended for children under the age of 16. If a child under the age of 13 has provided personally identifiable information to Yanmar through our website, a parent or guardian may contact **marketing@yanmar.com** to request the information be deleted from our records. Following receipt of such a request, Yanmar will make reasonable efforts to delete the child’s information from our records.

### California Residents Only:

The California “Shine the Light Law,” California Civil Code Section 1798.83, permits California residents to request and obtain once a year, free of charge, information about Personal Information (as defined by California law), if any, that we disclose to certain third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. California residents may make such a request in writing by emailing **marketing@yanmar.com** with your name and address, and noting “California Shine the Light Request” in the subject line of the email. Within 30 days of receiving your request, and where required by law, we will send you a list of the categories of personal information disclosed for third-party direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, along with the names and addresses of these third parties.

### Changes to this Statement

We will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect company and customer feedback. We encourage you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how we use your information.

### Contact Information

The Designated Data Controller is:

Information Technology Manager  
marketing@yanmar.com  
770-877-9894

If you notice any unlawful use of Personally Identifiable Information or if you believe that we have not adhered to this Statement, we would be grateful if you would notify us by email to  **marketing@yanmar.com.**
